Guide to the Donald F. Clark Collection circa 1642-1920 MS 118
New-York Historical Society
Donald F. Clark collection
circa 1642-1920
New-York Historical Society
Clark, Donald F., -1980
MS 118
5.5 Linear feet in 6 boxes + oversize documents
The collection, which was assembled by historian Donald F. Clark (died 1980), includes account books, church records, commissions, military records, and many other documentary forms that reflect Clark's interest in Orange County, New York during the Revolutionary War period and the Federalist era, with some materials into the later nineteenth and early twentieth centuries. It includes many pieces of correspondence to and from Governor George Clinton, as well as items written by or regarding notable figures including George Washington, Aaron Burr, the founders of Jamestown, Virginia, Nathaniel Woodhull, Richard Varick, John Hancock, Philip Schuyler, and many others.
Biographical Note
Donald F. Clark, an antiquarian, served as historian of Orange County, New York from 1969-1980 and chairman of the Orange County American Revolution Bicentennial Commission, circa 1974-1976.
BibliographySources:
"Orange County Historian." Orange County New York. Accessed August 20, 2015. http://www.orangecountygov.com/content/124/1338/10640/default.aspx.
"Clark Renamed Historian." The Evening News, January 20, 1970. Accessed August 8, 2015. https://news.google.com/newspapers?id=rYJGAAAAIBAJ&sjid=zywNAAAAIBAJ&pg=3803,2933994.
"Marks Battle Date." The Evening News, October 8, 1974. Accessed August 20, 2015. https://news.google.com/newspapers?id=pFNRAAAAIBAJ&sjid=qzMNAAAAIBAJ&pg=6048,1440470.
Scope and Contents Note
The collection, which was assembled by Clark, includes account books; church records; commissions; correspondence; court records; muster rolls and other military records; receipts; currency; and a variety of printed materials. The items collected reflect Clark's interest in Orange County, New York during the Revolutionary War period and the Federalist era, with some materials into the later nineteenth and early twentieth centuries.
Includes many pieces of correspondence to and from Governor George Clinton, as well as items written by or regarding notable figures including George Washington, Aaron Burr, the founders of Jamestown, Virginia, Nathaniel Woodhull, Richard Varick, John Hancock, Philip Schuyler, and many others.
The container list in this finding aid includes a detailed inventory for most, though not all, of the collection, that is, about 635 of the 795 items. A full hard-copy, typescript list is available in the Reading Room.
Access Restrictions
For more information on making arrangements to consult the collection, please visit www.nyhistory.org/library/visit.
Separated Materials Note
Newspapers and broadsides from the collection were moved to the Library's General Collection and cataloged individually at an earlier date. To locate these items, search "Donald F. Clark" in the online catalog.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Bequest of Donald F. Clark, October 9th, 1980. Some items from the collection were returned to the Clark estate in 1983. These items are marked in the inventory with the phrase, "Original returned, photocopy only."
Arrangement
The items in the collection are physically arranged by a sequential item designation (numbered 1-795) given to individual documents (or small sets of documents) at some point in time, either originally by Clark or by Michelle Figliomeni who inventoried the items in July 1980. Because that sequencing has no perceptible order, this finding aid lists the documents in chronological order, with undated items at the end. As of May 2022, Figliomeni's list of 795 items has not yet been fully transcribed for this on-line finding aid and so the list includes items only to number 634 and 742-744. Figliomeni's full hard-copy list is available in the Reading Room. For the present, the untranscribed items are summarized at the box level at the end of this container list.
Existence and Location of Copies
Microfilm copy available.
Other Finding Aids
The original, complete item list of the collection (795 items) prepared by Michelle P. Figliomeni in July 1980 is available in the N-YHS Reading Room.
Account books.; Commissions (orders for works).; Church records and registers; Court records; Deeds.; Diaries.; Muster rolls.; Payrolls; Orange County (N.Y.); United States -- History -- Revolution, 1775-1783.; Alexander, William, 1726-1783; Clinton, George, 1739-1812; Duer, William Alexander, 1780-1858; Fish, Hamilton, 1808-1893; Hancock, John, 1737-1793; Haring, John, 1739-1809; Jackson, Andrew, 1767-1845; Livingston, Robert R., 1746-1813; Knox, Henry, 1750-1806; McDougall, Alexander, 1732-1786; Pickering, Timothy, 1745-1829; Van Buren, Martin, 1782-1862; Woodhull, Nathaniel, 1722-1776
- Meade, William. Letter to brother and sister, 1653 April 24 (Box 5, Item 579)
- Provost, Johannis. Account with Gideon Schauer, 1669 (Box 3, Item 357)
- William and Mary. Proclamation regarding Benjamin Fletcher, Governor of the Colony of New York, 1697 May 2 (Box 5, Item 588)
- County of Essex, MA. Grand Jury inquest and return regarding Hossan (?) Rogers, mother of murdered child, 1700 November 13 (Box 2, Item 219)
- Denne, Chris, original Wawayanda patentee. Indenture between John Everet and Samuel Clows. Wawayanda, Orange County, N.Y., 1714 October 8 (Box 2, Item 247)
- Carpenter, Benjamin, John and Solomon. Assorted papers. Orange County, N.Y., 1714-1796 (Box 2, Item 248)
  Scope and Contents
  Deeds, wills receipts, guardians, petitions.
- Bassett, William. Copy of order for arrest of George Lachemy to Sheriff. County of Plymouth, MA, 1716 April 3 (Box 2, Item 221)
- Clark, John C. Deed of gift to his seven children. Middletown, CT, 1720 September 4 (Box 3, Item 321)
- Boudinot, E. and G. Cortland. Judgment entered, 1725 May 22 (Box 2, Item 174)
- Phipps, Samuel. Affidavit, 1727 June 14 (Box 2, Item 222)
- Haringh, Abraham. Order to Constable. Orange County, New York., 1730 May 26 (Box 3, Item 473)
  Bring before Haringh, William Barker, David Johnson, Charles Clifford, and Henry Low.
- Smith, William and Thomas Nable. Indenture, partial. Newburgh, 1744 (Box 1, Item 157)
- Commissioners for Distribution of Moiety of Prizes taken. Letter to Colonial Governor George Clinton, 1744 May 18 (Box 1, Item 129)
  Prizes taken from Spaniards from July 10, 1739 to October 19, 1740 by British ships of war.
- Wiloman, Henry. Will, 1745 May 20 (Box 1, Item 124)
- Wiloman, Henry. Confirmation of mortgage to Stephen DeLancey. New York City, 1745 July 4 (Box 4, Item 504)
  Signed by Cadwallader Colden, Colonial Governor of New York.
- Alexander, Mary, mother of Lord Stirling. Receipt. New York, 1747 June 26 (Box 2, Item 204)
- Clinton, George. Commission to Jacob Blackwell, 1748 September 3 (Box 3, Item 375)
- Miller, Peter Johannes. Genealogical information, 1750-1757 (Box 4, Item 565)
  Photostat. Belongs with #566. In German.
- Colman, Samuel and William Hudson. Deed. Orange County, NY, 1751 May 23 (Box 2, Item 239)
- Clinton, George, Governor of New York. Grant of Petition of John Luke for land in Ulster County. Deed (patent), 1751 October 18 (Box 5, Item 602)
- Bishop, Samuel. Deed with David Slauson. Stamford, Fairfield County, CT, 1754 April 24 (Box 5, Item 596)
- Wynkoop, John D. Receipt Received of Stephen Nottingham, 1755 March 22 (Box 1, Item 44)
- George II. Appointment of Justices of the Peace in Dutchess County, NY, 1755 May 6 (Box 5, Item 611)
- Parsons, William. Letter to Conrad Weiser, Esq. Camp at Harris's, 1756 May 23 (Box 2, Item 300)
  Fresh horse for delivering papers.
- Daniel Emblers. Record Book. Records baptisms, items sold, communicanten register, 1756-1823 (Box 4, Item 566)
- Bradstreet, John. Note to Abraham Mortier, Paymaster General at New York. Albany, NY, 1758 December 5 (Box 1, Item 48)
- George II. Appointment of George Clinton as Clerk of the Court of Common Pleas in Ulster County, 1759 (Box 4, Item 560)
  Seal.
- Sealy, Mary. Permission to Benjamin Allifor to have her gun, 1759 September 9 (Box 3, Item 467)
- Hasbrouck, Jr., Abraham. Deed with Jacob Griffen. Kingston, Ulster County, NY, 1760 December 1 (Box 4, Item 561)
- Colden, Cadwallader, Colonial Governor of New York. Commission to Jacob Blackwell, 1761 June 1 (Box 4, Item 505)
  Rank of Major.
- Foord, Elisha. Tea receipt, 1761 September 23 (Box 3, Item 449)
- Account book. Kingston, NY, 1761-1808 (Box 6, Item 625)
- Colden, Cadwallader, Colonial Governor of New York. Commission for Cornelius Vandyk, 1762 March 20 (Box 4, Item 490)
  Rank of Captain.
- Moore, Thomas. Indenture with Lambert Moore. Peekskill, NY, 1763 April 23 (Box 3, Item 415)
  Photocopy only, original returned.
- Moore, Thomas. Deed to Samuel Moore. Ulster County, 1764 November 20 (Box 3, Item 409)
- Erskine, Robert. Letter to John Calcraft. London, 1765 June 27 (Box 3, Item 374)
- Sackett, Hannah. Indenture with Joseph Sackett, 1765 September 24 (Box 1, Item 156)
  Orange County, New York.
- Clinton, Charles. Petition to build a church meetinghouse, 1765 November 23 (Box 2, Item 186)
  Signed by many local residents including George Clinton, Alexander Falls, and James Burnet.
- George III. Act of Parliament for Punishing Mutiny and Desertion and for Better Pay of the Army and Their Quarters, 1767 (Box 4, Item 511)
- Coleman, Joab and Assayel Coleman. Deed. Cornwall, Orange County, NY, 1767 July 23 (Box 2, Item 234)
- Hecht, Frederick William, Deputy Commissioner. Letter to William Cockburn, Surveyor General. New York, 1769 April 10 (Box 2, Item 175)
  Tract of land, Ulster County.
- Hudson, John and William Hudson. Deed. Orange County, NY, 1769 June 1 (Box 2, Item 237)
- Hudson, William. Deed. Orange County, NY, 1769 June 2 (Box 2, Item 236)
- Robinson, Beverly. Sworn statement before Daniel Horsmanden, 1770 January 26 (Box 3, Item 414)
  Concerning Henry Van Schaack.
- Southard, John and James Duncan, Esq. Deed with Michael Frederick. New York County, 1770 February 12 (Box 3, Item 439)
- Low, Isaac. Letter to Mr. Jellis Fonda, merchant. New York, NY, 1770 May 23 (Box 1, Item 43)
- Burnet, Robert. Deed with Robert Burnet, Jr. New Windsor, 1770 December 22 (Box 3, Item 459)
- Colony of New York Currency. 3 pounds, 1771 February 16 (Box 1, Item 37)
- Foord, Elisha. Tea receipt. Boston, 1771 October 22 (Box 3, Item 445)
- Smith, William, deceased. Auction listing, 1772 March 9 (Box 3, Item 410)
  Chesecock patent lands, lands near Hudson River, lands near Ramapo Creek.
- Foord, Elisha. Tea receipt. Boston, 1772 July 2 (Box 3, Item 442)
- Foord, Elisha. Tea receipt. Boston, 1772 August 14 (Box 3, Item 443)
- Foord, Elisha. Tea receipt. Boston, 1772 December 18 (Box 3, Item 448)
- Dederick, Christina. Note. West Camp, 1773 August 8 (Box 3, Item 343)
- Mathews, Vincent. Letter to Brother. Mathewsfield, 1773 November 9 (Box 2, Item 179)
  Original returned, photocopy only. Regarding surveying land and John Dubois' defalcation.
- Stirling, William Alexander (Lord). Letter to Mr. John Concklin and Mr. Joseph Concklin. New York, 1774 February 9 (Box 3, Item 397)
  Chesecocks patent.
- Haring, John. Sworn Oath. Orange Town, New York, 1774 March 21 (Box 2, Item 172)
  Witnessed by Daniel Horsemanden.
- Smith, William. Letter to Col. James Clinton, 1774 April 8 (Box 1, Item 121)
  "Governor Tryon sailed yesterday" enclosing package received before he embarked.
- Livingston, Philip I. Writ. Promise of Benjamin Haight to appear. Dutchess County, 1774 May 17 (Box 6, Item 630)
- Dederick, Christina. Note. West Camp in Ulster County, 1774 June 25 (Box 3, Item 344)
- Foord, Elisha. Tea receipt. Pembroke, 1774 August 2 (Box 3, Item 444)
- Foord, Elisha. Tea receipt. Marshfield, 1774 November 15 (Box 3, Item 446)
- General Committee for the City and County of New York. Broadside to the Freeholders and Freemen of the City and County of New York. Call for General Committee to be Elected, 1775 April 28 (Box 6, Item 619)
  Original returned, photocopy only.
- Cuyper, Theunis. Note to pay $5 by Misol Vrobiey, 1775 June 5 (Box 2, Item 211)
- Carleton, Sir Guy. Montreal, 1775 June 24 (Box 1, Item 117)
  Document is in French.
- Hancock, John. Appointment of James Clinton, Esq. to Colonel of the Third Regiment of the New York Forces. Philadelphia, 1775 June 30 (Box 2, Item 240)
  Facsimile.
- Burnet, Robert. Lease to George Clinton. New Windsor, 1775 July 17 (Box 3, Item 460)
- Burnet, Robert. Bond to George Clinton. New Windsor, 1775 July 18 (Box 3, Item 462)
- Haring, John. Blank printed form for Committee of Safety for the Colony of New York, 1775 August 22 (Box 4, Item 530)
- Colony of New York. Currency. Three dollars. John Holt, printer, 1775 September 2 (Box 3, Item 390)
- Van Schaack, Peter. Letter to L. Gansvoort, 1775 October (Box 3, Item 392)
  Unable to file Bill of Foreclosure. Governor William Tryon aboard the Asia fear of custody.
- Curtiss, Israel. Letter to Col. Jonathan Chase. Camp North. St. John's, Canada, 1775 October 7 (Box 1, Item 10)
- Smith, Joshua. Revolutionary War Commissary Order for Commissary General Jeremiah Wadsworth, 1775 October 12 (Box 3, Item 345)
  Order for flour and peas from Sam McClellan, merchant in Woodstock.
- Woodhull, Nathaniel. Appointment of Samuel Lyon as Second Major of the Regiment of Minutemen of West Chester County. Colony of New York, 1775 October 27 (Box 2, Item 289)
- Coleman, John, clerk. Letter to Daniel Gerow, 1775 November 18 (Box 3, Item 468)
  Order to appear.
- Colony of New York Two Dollar Bill. Printed by John Holt, 1775 (Box 2, Item 214)
- Bancker, Gerard, Treasurer of New York State. Account of Monies Paid, 1775-1776 (Box 2, Item 283)
  Attached letter by Comfort Sands.
- McConnell, Samuel. Letter to Wife. Cambridge College, 1776 January 20 (Box 1, Item 82)
- Woodhull, Nathaniel. Appointment of Abraham Dolson as Captain of a Company of Militia. Colony of New York, 1776 February 29 (Box 2, Item 288)
- Stirling, William Alexander, Lord. Receipt for six inch spikes, 1776 March 5 (Box 3, Item 373)
- Contemporaneous copy of the Resolutions of the New York Provincial Congress, 1776 May 31 (Box 1, Item 26)
  Resolutions regarding elections and governance.
- Varick, Richard. Letter. Albany, 1776 June 20 (Box 2, Item 293)
  Regarding General's interest in the department.
- Lamb, James, ADC. Letter to Christopher Yates. Fort George, 1776 June 30 (Box 2, Item 292)
  Regarding order.
- Glen, Henry. Letter to Jellis Fonda. Schnectady, 1776 July 8 (Box 2, Item 177)
  Request regarding flour.
- Bogart, Claus. Permit for Daniel Gerow to recover four pounds from John Wickman. Orange County, 1776 August 5 (Box 3, Item 471)
- Washington, George (assumed). Letter to New York legislature, 1776 September 8 (Box 2, Item 198)
  Regarding appointment of General Clinton. Written by George Washington. Missing signature page.
- Clinton, George. Letter to John McKesson at Fishkill. Kingsbridge, 1776 September 26 (Box 3, Item 411)
  Expedition against Montressor's Island; Inquiry into conduct of Captain Wisner.
- Varick, Richard. Letter to Christopher J. Yates, Esq. Cheshires on Wood Creek, 1776 October 6 (Box 3, Item 385)
  Troops keep sawmill running day and night.
- Livingston, P.R. Letter to father, 1776 October 10 (Box 1, Item 92)
  Regarding letter from headquarters, 2 ships have passed our obstruction. Troops concealed and mean to take possession of the land.
- Benson, Robert. Extract from Minutes of Committee of Safety for the State of New York. Fish Kills, 1776 October 10 (Box 1, Item 94)
  Original returned, photocopy only. Establish post riders to gather daily intelligence.
- Hancock, John, President of the Continental Congress. Commission to John Hodge. Philadelphia, 1776 October 10 (Box 4, Item 555)
  Hodge named Captain of Frigate, Montgomery. Contains John Hancock's signature.
- Duer, Colonel William. Letter to Governor James Clinton. Fishkills, 1776 October 30 (Box 2, Item 173)
  Letter stating enemy vessels in the river are planning attack.
- Wisner, Harry. Account of work done on Sterling Road by orders of Convention and Direction of Harry Wisner, Esq., 1776 November (Box 3, Item 303)
  Original returned, photocopy only. Amount signed off by Comfort Sands.
- Livingston, Robert R. Letter to Edward Rutledge, Esq. Fishkills, 1776 November 13 (Box 1, Item 128)
  Regarding forming our government, fortifying our frontier.
- Livingston, James. Copy of payroll of field staff of Colonel James Livingston's Battalion, 1776 November 20-1777 August 31 (Box 3, Item 481)
- Alexander, William, 6th Pennsylvania Battalion. Letter to Major Frazer. Mt. Independence, VT, 1776 November 26 (Box 3, Item 418)
  Complaints regarding bad beef.
- Wisner, Harry. Memorandum regarding chain broke by strength of tides in Hudson River, 1776 December 12 (Box 3, Item 304)
- Robichaux, James. Military payroll of Captain James Robichaux's Company of Colonel Livingston's Battalion, 1779 December 27 (Box 4, Item 488)
- State of New York Ten Dollar Bill. Printed by Samel Loudon, 1776 (Box 2, Item 215)
- Colony of New York One-Third of Dollar (2 shillings & 8 pence). Printed by Samuel Loudon, 1776 (Box 2, Item 216)
- Colony of New York Five Dollar Bill. Printed by Samuel Loudon, 1776 (Box 2, Item 217)
- Colony of New York One-Half Dollar Bill. Printed by Samuel Loudon, 1776 (Box 2, Item 218)
- Schuyler, Philip. Letter. Albany, 1777 January 5 (Box 1, Item 142)
  Regarding news of glorious victory.
- Clinton, Maj. Gen. George. Letter to Capt. Woodhull. New Windsor, 1777 January 15 (Box 3, Item 406)
  Original returned, photocopy only. Discusses seizing Palmer and bringing him before Clinton.
- Lamb, Alexander. Receipt of Daniel Gerow. New City, 1777 January 30 (Box 3, Item 469)
- Schuyler, Philip. Letter to the Commanding Officer at Fish Kill. Albany, NY, 1777 March 19 (Box 1, Item 32)
  Original returned, photocopy only. Short marginal note by James Clinton, brigadier general.
- Warner, Captain Nathan. Return of the Main Guard, 1777 April 16 (Box 1, Item 111)
- Benson, Egbert. Bill from state of New York, 1777 April 23 (Box 2, Item 291)
- Clinton, Brig. Gen. James. Letter to commanding officer at Ramapough Clove. Fort Montgomery, 1777 April 29 (Box 3, Item 306)
  Original returned, photocopy only. Account of party of Tories.
- Congress. Broadside. Resolutions regarding Army and Commissary of Forage. Philadelphia, 1777 May 14 (Box 6, Item 620)
- Dixon, Matthew. Payroll of the Engineering Department under Major Matthew Dixon, Chief Engineer. New York, 1777 May 20 (Box 2, Item 199)
  List of men, rank, and salary.
- Roesell, Ludwigh and Thomas V. Steenbergh. Letter to Mr. Emrich, 1777 June 19 (Box 3, Item 334)
  Original returned, photocopy only. Regarding canoe and sail to Fort Montgomery.
- Smith, Melancton, Sheriff. Indenture. County of Dutchess, 1777 June 26 (Box 2, Item 243)
  Regarding elections.
- Wallace, J. Sir. Letter to Vice Admiral Lord. On board experiment, 1777 July 8 (Box 3, Item 314)
  Regarding convoy in Catwaters not showing signals.
- Wheaton, Comfort, Captain of the Provost. Requistion for prisoners' supplies to Capt. Asa Waterman, 1777 July 21 (Box 1, Item 31)
- Pye, David, Justice of Haverstraw Precinct, Orange County. Permit for Daniel Gerow to Pass. Orange County, 1777 August 2 (Box 3, Item 470)
  Home to Schalesberg, Bergen County and return.
- Worthington, Asa. Letter to Ebenezer Foote. At Colonel Griffen's, 1777 August 7 (Box 5, Item 593)
- Forts Montgomery and Clinton. Broadside regarding Return of Prisoners taken at Forts Montgomery and Clinton, 1777 October (Box 5, Item 612)
- Bayrd, John. Order on the Continental Congress for J. Crawford, 1777 October 13 (Box 1, Item 123)
- Elmendorph, Lt. Col. Jonathan. Letter to Captain Dederick. Kingston, 1777 October 14 (Box 3, Item 335)
  Original returned, photocopy only. Letter regarding enemy's destruction of Peenpaugh.
- Clinton, George. Letter to Brother, James Clinton. Hurley, 1777 October 17 (Box 3, Item 348)
- Clinton, George. Letter to Colonel Samuel Webb. Poughkeepsie, 1777 October 25 (Box 2, Item 297)
- Clinton, George. Letter to Col. Samuel Webb. New Windsor, 1777 November 7 (Box 2, Item 295)
  Original returned, photocopy only. Regarding sending items to Fort Montgomery.
- House, Elizabeth. Certification that Daniel Gerow delivered cattle and slaves, 1777 November 9 (Box 3, Item 472)
- Hughes, Timothy. Military payroll of Captain Timothy Hughes' Company of Colonel James Livingston's Battalion, 1777 December 12 (Box 4, Item 491)
- State of New York. Constitution. Printed by Styner & Cist, Philadelphia, 1777 (Box 4, Item 523)
  32 pages
- State of New York. Constitution. Printed by Samuel Loudon, Fishkill, 1777 (Box 4, Item 524)
  33 pages
- Van Rensselaer, Peter. Military payroll of Captain Peter Van Rensselaer's Company of Colonel James Livingston's Battalion, 1778 February (Box 3, Item 482)
- Clinton, George. Letter to Major Quakenboss, DQMG. Poughkeepsie, 1778 February 23 (Box 3, Item 327)
  Original returned, photocopy only. Purchase of boards to rebuild church.
- Clinton, George, Governor of New York. Commission to John Brewster, 1778 February 24 (Box 4, Item 507)
  Rank of First Lieutenant.
- Burgoyne, Lieutenant General John. Letter to John Powell, Department of Payment General to his Majesty's Forces, Quebec. Cambridge, 1778 March 3 (Box 5, Item 595)
  Pay subsistence for prisoners of war.
- (King George III) Marginal note: From the King to General Hervey. Remarks on the Conduct of the War from Canada. Queen's House, 1778 March 20 (Box 1, Item 45)
  Discussion of troop movements.
- State of New York. Broadside. Act for completing the 5 Continental Battalions raised by state, 1778 April 1 (Box 6, Item 621)
- Van Cortlandt, Pierre. Disbursement to Robert Benson from State of New York, 1778 April 5 (Box 3, Item 330)
- Heath, Major General William. Letter to Ebenezer Hancock. Headquarters Boston, 1778 April 7 (Box 3, Item 372)
  Payment for hospital stores.
- State of Massachusetts-Bay. Broadside. Resolutions regarding brigades. Copy, 1778 April 20 (Box 6, Item 622)
- Howe, General Robert. Letter assumed to be to the President of the Continental Congress. Savannah, 1778 April 26 (Box 3, Item 349)
  War conditions in Florida.
- Mott, Gershom, Captain of Artillery. Receipt. Fishkill, 1778 May 28 (Box 1, Item 108)
  Original returned, photocopy only. Received horses.
- Petition of South Orange County Inhabitants, 1778 July (Box 3, Item 360)
  Original returned, photocopy only. Captain Bell's order to join General Greyham in White Plains.
- Livingston, Colonel William. Receipt for shoes and stockings. Windham, 1778 July 31 (Box 5, Item 589)
- Pratt, John, Assistant Commanding General under James Clinton. Bond for $5,000, 1778 August 9 (Box 2, Item 178)
- Van Rensselaer, Peter. Military payroll of Captain Peter Van Rensselaer's Company of Colonel James Livingston's Battalion, 1778 August and September (Box 4, Item 485)
- Van Rensselaer, Peter. Military payroll of Captain Peter Van Rensselaer's Company of Colonel James Livingston's Battalion, 1778 September (Box 3, Item 484)
- Bruen, H., DQMG. Letter to Brigadier General Pattison, Commanding the Royal Artillery. New York, NY, 1778 September 3 (Box 1, Item 93)
- Dieterich, Lorentz. Affidavit. Winterhill, 1778 September 7 (Box 3, Item 340)
- Morehouse, Colonel Receipt. Fishkill Landing, 1778 October 9 (Box 2, Item 253)
- Carpenter, Nehemiah. Deposition before John Robinson, Justice. Ulster County, 1778 October 22 (Box 3, Item 305)
  Original returned, photocopy only. Regarding destruction of property by British.
- Elmendorph, Lt. Colonel Jonathan. Letter to Captain Dederick. Hurley, 1778 October 24 (Box 3, Item 336)
  Original returned, photocopy only. Regarding company's tour of duty.
- Loudon, Samuel. Letter to Joseph Bullock, Lottery Manager, Philadelphia. Fishkill, 1778 November 11 (Box 2, Item 287)